### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ zainahamedux (LinkedIn) znap.link/zainahamed (Personal)

### Top Skills

Design
User Interface Design
Problem Solving

### Languages

Sinhala (Professional Working)
Tamil (Native or Bilingual)
English (Full Professional)

### Certifications

Digital Skills: User Experience
User Experience Design Essentials Adobe XD UI UX Design
7-Day UX Course Certificate
Start the UX Design Process:
Empathize, Define, and Ideate
Foundations of User Experience
(UX) Design

# Zain A.

**UI/UX** Designer

Colombo District, Western Province, Sri Lanka

### Summary

"There is no proof that we all see the same colors."

It's evident that digital has taken over. Whether you're a business or an individual, your online presence is more important than ever in your mission to scale, impact, or serve. In truth, attention is the new currency.

Along with the digital world, design plays a major role to take over the world. Attention is sought through design and to take over you with the right amount of pepperoni in design.

I am Zain Ahamed. A passionate, skillful, motivated UI UX Designer (Part-time Web Developer) who spent 3 years of experience in the design industry.

Worked as a Graphic Designer at AH Printers and as a Creative Designer via Freelancing and gained more knowledge with design theory and modules.

Currently working as a User Experience Designer at Cabbage Apps and parallelly studying Pearson's BTEC HND in Computing - Application Development (Solent University - UK) at BCAS Campus Kandy with hands-on skills in programming and front-end web development.

And yes. I am still learning more. There's no right age to learn and master new things. Bring up your concepts and let me polish your ideas into a bright-looking star and skyrocket it!

My personal goal in every endeavor is to increase the capacity of myself, and those around me, to create a community committed to excellence and integrity, online and offline.

I would be honored to have you learn along my timeline.

To Your Prosperity,

Zain Ahamed

Let's build a relationship!
Say Hi: zainahamedux@gmail.com
Instagram Work : zainahamedux

### Experience

Calcey
UX Designer
January 2023 - Present (9 months)
Colombo, Western Province, Sri Lanka

- Work closely with Customers, Business Analysts, and Project Managers to understand the business requirements
- Produce and manage design assets for use of the development team
- Creative design ability and good knowledge of UX design best practices
- Being knowledgeable and up-to-date on software development lifecycle and best practices
- Take ownership of the UX development of an assigned project
- Ability to create mock-ups, designs, and wireframes
- Provide time estimates
- Collaborate across design, engineering, and management teams within an Agile development environment
- Strong end-user perspective and empathy when developing software applications
- Willingness to learn the latest technology and UX trends
- Actively participate in requirement elaboration discussions and client meetings
- Translate complex product requirements into easy and intuitive user flows
- Develop, produce, and iterate wireframes, user flows, information architecture diagrams, and prototypes for both web and mobile experiences

CabbageApps
User Experience Designer
March 2021 - January 2023 (1 year 11 months)
Colombo, Western, Sri Lanka

Enrolled in CabbageApps! Even in a remote position at CA, provided a comfortable journey and hardworking environment to build a better career throughout the days.

- Create design concepts and drawings to determine the best product.
- Present product ideas to relevant team members for brainstorming.
- Suggest improvements to design and performance to engineers.
- Maintain up to date on current industry trends and market conditions
- Modify and revise existing designs to meet customer expectations
- Consider comfort and usability when designing new products
- Define and design example interaction patterns through documentation and prototypes
- Contribute new ideas to help evolve the capabilities of the products
- Gather and evaluate user requirements, in collaboration with product managers and engineers
- Identify and troubleshoot UX problems (e.g. responsiveness, user-flow)
- Develop and conceptualize a comprehensive UI/UX design strategy for the brand
- Produce high-quality UX design solutions through wireframes, visual and graphic designs, flow diagrams, storyboards, site maps, and prototypes
- Providing advice and guidance on the implementation of UX research methodologies and testing activities in order to analyze and predict user behavior
- Create user-centered designs by understanding business requirements, the voice of the customer, user journeys, customer feedback, and usability findings
- Working knowledge of programming (HTML/CSS)
- And well experienced in WebFlow

#### Fox Labs

User Interface Designer | Social Media Marketing Designer June 2020 - February 2021 (9 months)

Kandy, Central, Sri Lanka

Enrolled in Fox Labs as a UI designer and bringing in a new impression by desire and willingness to deliver a great outcome for our clients. Monitoring the progress of the team, organizing, implementing new ideas, and boosting up performances in the team to attain the team's expected goals.

- Gathering and evaluating user requirements, in collaboration with product managers and engineers.
- Creating creative designs and marketing strategies for Startups

- Illustrating design ideas using storyboards, process flows, sitemaps, and wireframes.
- Guiding the development, maintenance, and allocation of resources to attain organizational goals.
- Ability to work effectively in a collaborative environment to create topperforming interfaces.
- Advanced problem-solving skills and the ability to optimize data for the best possible outcome.
- Time-management skills, with the ability to rapidly test and iterate designs.
- Team spirit and good communication skills to collaborate with various stakeholders.

### Freelance

Creative Designer

October 2017 - May 2018 (8 months)

Unleashing your own self out is when you work hard own your stand and bring in the right amount of essence to your life. It might sound easy at first but Freelancing gives you all the effort that you need to bring yourself out.

#### What I learned:

- Experience in working with freelancing sites and handling clients.
- Vast knowledge of design theory and skills.
- · Understanding and interpreting client briefs.
- Extensively using industry-standard software such as Adobe Creative Suite.

Check out some freelancing links below

### **AH Printers**

**Graphic Designer** 

February 2017 - March 2018 (1 year 2 months)

Kandy District, Central, Sri Lanka

An organization with all kinds of designing and printing.

- Accountable for overall Graphic Designing at the organization.
- All kinds of designing of own work and printing.
- Managed multidisciplinary roles at the organization. (IT Administrator, Graphic Designer, Network Engineer, and System Maintenance, more)
- Maintaining and managing network, data, and resources including software and Hardware upgrading based on the requirement.
- Troubleshooting hardware, software, and network issues and doing services.

## Education

Solent University

Pearson BTEC Higher National Diploma, Computing (Application Development) · (2019 - 2021)